https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlosmougan/ https://github.com/cmougan

## Professional Summary

During the last years, I have conducted research for some of the best national research institutes in Deep Learning in the National Research Council and Data Science in Barcelona Supercomputing Center. I have experience working as a Robotics consultant in Deloitte, where I had the opportunity to work as a team leader an be in charge of the delivery of projects. I have joined numerous data science competitions: 1st Boston Consulting Group Gamma Datathon, 3rd Accenture Health Datathon, 2nd at SpainML Telco-churn and Bronze Medal at Kaggle IEEE-CIS Fraud Detection.

## EXPERIENCE

## The Alan Turing Institute

London, United Kingdom

Email: carmougan@gmail.com

Mobile:  $+34\ 620\ 618\ 275$ 

Aug-Sep 2019

University of Bristol

o Data Science Facilitator: With the Alan Turing Institute and the University of Bristol I was a Data Science Facilitator for the Data Case Study Group with a team of 10 researchers and Data Scientist tackling air pollution and traffic for the Bristol City Council.

## Barcelona SuperComputing Center

Barcelona, Spain

Applied Learning Methods

April 2019 - Aug 2019

o Research Data Scientist: This research line explores the use of Learning Techniques to different domains, from data centre optimization to cancer genomics, leveraging different techniques from statistical Machine Learning to state of the art Deep Learning and Neural Networks, and different programming frameworks.

#### **CSIC-IIIA**

Barcelona, Spain

Instituto de Investigacion Inteligancia Artificial del CSIC

Jan 2019 - July 2018

o Deep Learning PreDoctoral Research: Improving and applying Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) to approach large scale combinatorial optimization problems.

### **Deloitte Robotics**

Madrid, Spain

Technological Consultant

Dec 2017 - August 2018

- Team Leader: Coordinated a team of two developers, a machine learning engineer and two data analyst applying Cognitive Automation (CA) to the Audit Process. Implementing Machine Learning to the extraction (OCR) and the classification of unstructured data with WorkFusion. I took part in the delivery of the project where we were able to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of their operations by a 70%.
- **UiPath Trainer**: UiPath trainer to the international Deloitte's team of Belgium and Netherlands.
- o Naoqi Developer: Developing functions for the robots of SoftBank Pepper and Nao for commercial and marketing purposes. We collaborated in events and workshops were Pepper was in charge of 'chairing' and introducing the speakers.
- Uipath Developer: Developer for a leading national banking company where we automated two processes. In the delivery of the project we obtained automation of a 100% and an 80% respectively, allowing workers to focus on more creative tasks.

# AEMET

Madrid, Spain

Agencia Estatal de Meteorología

Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

o Internship: at the Prediction and Modelling Department with a University collaboration where I modelled and predicted the atmospheric pollution of the northern side of Italy.

## EDUCATION

#### Universitat Autónoma de Barcelona

Barcelona, Spain

Master in Mathematical Modelling: Data Science

Sept. 2018 - Current

## Universidad Complutense de Madrid

Madrid, Spain

Degree in Physics

Sept. 2013 - Feb 2018

Specialized in Atmospheric Physics and Astrophysics: Dissertation in 'Atmospheric Contamination Modelling'.

### Saint Paul Preparatory High School

Minnesota, US

International baccalaureate

o Honor International Student at Saint Paul Preparatory: Received a Scholarship for international students with an excellent curriculum (€10,000).

# OTHER INFORMATION

- Languages: Spanish(Native), English (Fluent, C1).
- Volunteering with Refugees(Athens) April 2017: Volunteering experience working alongside war refugees trying to improve their environment
- Elite Swimming Athlete 2013 -2017: National recognition for athletes with an outstanding performance. Achievements: Finalist of the Spanish Olympic Trials 2016, 3<sup>rd</sup> Team in Spanish Honor Division, 2012 Minnesota State Champions as Individual & Team. Record holder of several state events.